cardano.org 2019-07-04

# CardanoFoundation(CardanoStiftung)isanotforprofitorganisationbasedinZug, Switzerlandthatisdedicatedtoactasanobjective,supervisoryandeducational bodyfortheCardanoProtocolanditsassociatedecosystem.Theregistered addressis:CardanoStiftung,Dammstrasse16,Zug,6300,Switzerland.Weworkin close cooperation with our partners IOHK and Emurgo.

Privacy Policy
This Policy (together with our ​Terms of Use​) explains and sets out the basis for why
and when we collect personal information about the people who visit our website(s),
how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and the
measures we take to keep it secure.
By visiting this website you are accepting and consenting to the practices described
in this policy. Please note that this includes consenting to the collection and
processing of any personal information you provide, as described below.
We may amend this Policy from time to time so please check it occasionally to
ensure that you agree with any changes. Your continued use of our website(s) will
constitute your acceptance of, and agreement to, any changes.
Any questions regarding this policy and our privacy practices should be sent by
email to gdpr@cardano.org or by writing to Cardano Foundation, Dammstrasse 16,
Zug, 6300, Switzerland.
Who we are?
Cardano Foundation (Cardano Stiftung) is a not for profit organisation based in Zug,
Switzerland that is dedicated to act as an objective, supervisory and educational
body for the Cardano Protocol and its associated ecosystem . The registered
address is: Cardano Stiftung, Dammstrasse 16, Zug, 6300, Switzerland. We work in
close cooperation with our partners IOHK and Emurgo.
                                                                            Page 1/10

How we collect information about you:
We obtain information about you when you use our website, when you contact us via
email or a web form or if you register to receive one of our regular newsletters.
We may collect and process the following types of information about you:
Information you provide us
You may provide us with personal information by filling in forms on our website(s) or
by corresponding with us by e-mail or live-chat.
The personal information you provide may include your name, email, address, phone
number, IP address, language preference and information regarding the pages you
access.
By providing us with this information, you expressly consent to our use of your
personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.
Information we collect about you
When you visit our website(s) we may collect information about your IP address,
information about your visit, your browsing activity, and how you use our website.
This information may be combined with other information you provide.
Information we receive from other sources
We may receive information about you if you use any other websites we, or our
partners, operate. We also work with third parties (including, contractors, project
partners, service providers, analytics providers) and may receive information about
you from them. This may be combined with other information you provide to us.
                                                                              Page 2/10

How your information is used
We may use personal information about you for the following purposes:
Marketing:
    ● to provide you with relevant information and news.
    ● to send you personalised communications which you have requested and that
       may be of interest to you, which may be based on your activity on our
       website(s) or the website of our partners. These may include information
       about campaigns, activities and events.
    ● to understand and measure the effectiveness of how we serve you and
       others.
    ● to make suggestions and recommendations to you about services that may
       interest you, which may be based on your activity on our website(s) or the
       website of our partners.
    ● for analytics and profiling to create aggregate trend reports, find out how
       visitors arrive at our website; which sites and pages are viewed, the
       responses to marketing campaigns and to determine the most effective
       marketing channels and messages.
    ● seek your views or comments on the service we provide
    ● notify you of changes to our service, policies and terms of use
We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. We will
hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the
relevant activity.
Who has access to your information
We will not sell or rent your information to third parties. We will not share your
information with third parties for marketing purposes.
We may pass your information to third party service providers, agents,
subcontractors and other associated organisations for the purposes of completing
tasks and providing services to you on our behalf (for example to process and store
information and to send you mails). However, if we use third party service providers,
                                                                           Page 3/10

we disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the service and
we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secure and
not to use it for their own direct marketing purposes.
We will take the necessary steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be
protected.
Your choices and your rights
You have the right to inform us not to process your personal information for
marketing purposes. You can exercise your right and prevent us from processing
such information by checking or unchecking certain boxes on the forms we use to
collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us by
email at gdpr@cardanofoundation.org
We will not contact you for marketing purposes unless you have given your prior
consent. You can change your marketing preferences at any time by contacting us
by email at gdpr@cardanofoundation.org.
How you can update your information
The accuracy of your information is important to us. if you change email address, or
any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at
gdpr@cardanofoundation.org
You have the right to ask for a copy of the information Cardano Foundation holds
about you.
Security measures to protect your information
When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that it’s treated
securely.
                                                                             Page 4/10

Non-sensitive details such as your email address may be transmitted unencrypted
over the Internet, and so may not be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive
to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any
information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. When we receive
your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.
Profiling
We may analyse your personal information to create a profile of your preferences
and interests so that we can contact you with information relevant to you. We may
make use of additional information about you when it is available from external
sources to help us do this effectively.
Newsletter
The provisions of this data privacy statement also apply to the request for and
sending of our newsletter.
The newsletter will only be sent after prior request by the user in the so-called
“double opt-in procedure” (request on our website and confirmation of a
corresponding request e-mail).
Users of the newsletter are also assigned a UserID, which allows Cardano
Foundation to determine when the relevant newsletter was opened and which links
or functions from the relevant newsletter were activated. This tracking is done for
internal optimization of the newsletter. This data will not be passed on to third
parties. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 f GDPR, where by Cardano
Foundation’s authorization arises from the fact that, on the one hand, Cardano
Foundation has an interest in evaluating such data for purposes of newsletter
optimisation and, on the other hand, a concerned person can reasonably foresee at
the time when the personal data is collected and in view of the circumstances under
which it is carried out (in particular the above-mentioned measures) that it will
possibly be processed for this purpose.
                                                                             Page 5/10

The user has the right to withdraw his or her consent at any time. If the user of the
newsletter does not wish to receive this tracking, he/she can unsubscribe from the
newsletter. To do so, simply unsubscribe via the link in the newsletter or send an
e-mail to gdpr@cardanofoundation.orgor send a message to the following address:
Cardano Stiftung, Dammstrasse 16, Zug, 6300, Switzerland
The withdrawal of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of processing based on
consent before its withdrawal.
Use of Cookies
Cookies are files or pieces of information that may be stored on your computer (or
other internet enabled devices, such as a smartphone or tablet) when you visit a
website. They are sent by a server to your computer and stored on your hard drive to
allow a website to recognise you when you visit. A cookie will usually contain the
name of the website from which the cookie has come from, the “lifetime” of the
cookie (i.e. how long it will remain on your device), and a value, which is usually a
randomly generated unique number.
Our website uses cookies. They collect statistical data about your browsing actions
and behaviour and do not identify you as an individual. Cookies may for example be
used to store your country or language preference. This helps to improve our
website and deliver a better service.
You may adjust the settings on your browser to refuse cookies but some of the
services on our website(s) may not work if you do so.
Cookie Policy
Our site(s) use cookies to distinguish you from other visitors of our site. This website
uses cookies. We use cookies to personalize content, to provide social media
features and to analyse our traffic. This improves your experience when you browse
our site(s) and allows us to improve the service we provide. By continuing to browse
our site(s), you are agreeing to our use of cookies.
                                                                               Page 6/10

We also share information about your use of our site with our social media and
analytics partners who may combine it with other information that you have provided
to them or that they have collected from your use of their services. Please review our
cookie policy, privacy policy and terms of use.
Cookies are small text files that may be stored on your computer (or other internet
enabled devices, such as a smartphone or tablet. They are sent by a server to your
computer and stored on your hard drive to allow a website to recognise you when
you visit. Cookies can be used by website to make user’s experience more efficient.
Our site(s) use different types of cookies. Some cookies are placed by third party
services that appear on our pages. You can at any time change or withdraw your
consent from the Cookie Declaration on our website.
Learn more about who we are, how you can contact us and how we process
personal data in our Privacy Policy
Your consent applies to the following domains: forum.cardano.org, cardano.org,
cardanofoundation.org
We use the following cookies:
Strictly Necessary Cookies
These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off
in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which
amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in
or filling in forms. These cookies enable basic functions like page navigation and
access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot functioning properly
without these cookies.
Targeting Cookies
These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. Marketing
cookies are used to track visitors across websites. They may be used by those
companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other
sites. The intention is to display ads that are relevant and engaging for the individual
user and thereby more valuable for publishers and third party advertisers. They do
not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your
                                                                              Page 7/10

browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience
less targeted advertising.
Performance Cookies
These cookies are usually referred to as statistical cookies and allow us to count
visits, traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site.
They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how
visitors move around the site. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and
therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies we will not know when you
have visited our site, and will not be able to monitor its performance.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites run by other organisations. This
privacy policy applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy
statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy
policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our
website.
If you linked to our website from a third party site, we cannot be responsible for the
privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third party site and
recommend that you check the policy of that site.
16 or Under
We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If you are
aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian’s permission beforehand
whenever you provide us with personal information.
Where we store your personal information
The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored in, a country
outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff
                                                                              Page 8/10

operating outside the EEA who work for us. The laws in some countries may not
provide the same legal protection for your information as in the EEA. By submitting
your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will
take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and
in accordance with this privacy policy.
The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although
we will always do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee
the security of your information; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have
received your information, we will use good procedures and strong security features
to try to prevent unauthorised access.
Data Protection Officer
Cardano Foundation is headquartered in Zug, Switzerland and has appointed an
internal data protection officer for you to contact if you have any questions or
concerns about our personal data policies or practices.
The data protection officer Tilmar W. Goos can be contacted as follows:
Cardano Stiftung
Dammstrasse 16
Zug, 6300
Switzerland
gdpr@cardano.org
Review of this Policy
We keep this Policy under regular review. This Policy was last updated in January
2019
                                                                            Page 9/10
